Guide to the Office of the Provost records, 1944-2011 RG0037
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Commission for the Year 2000, 1984-1985; RG0037 Series 5; 2 Linear feet (Box 3, Box 4, Box 1, Box 2)
  - Individual Faculty members, Students and Trustees comments on the Commission, 1984 ca. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes degrees granted, Graduate School of Arts and Sciences applicants, student registration, degrees conferred
  - Geographic Distribution, Tenure Accruing Faculty, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Commission's Mission Statement, 08/1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Statement of University Purpose and an Integrating Format
  - Agenda, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Report of faculty development, Institutional planning, Communications report (draft), Institute for Management Science, "A Policy Center at G.W.U., International Studies at G.W.U." (draft).
  - Outline of Report/ Summary of recommendations/ Mission of the University, Mission Statement of the Commission (draft), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Columbian College Departments, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Humanities, Performing Arts, Sciences, Mathematics, Statistics, American Studies, Art, Chemistry, Communications and Theatre
  - Departments, continued, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Science, Physics, Computer and Information Science, Mathematics, Biological Sciences, Geology
  - Departments, continued, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Departments, continued, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Religion, Romance Languages and Literatures, Speech and hearing
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Departments, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Sociology (Five year plan, Medical and Health Policy, Criminology and Deviance, Organizations and Occupations Gender. Forensic Sciences, Public Policy Programs, Women's Studies. School of Education and Human Development
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science, School of Government and Business Administration, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - SGBA continued, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Also Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Medical Center, National Law Center, School of Public and International Affairs
  - SPIA, "International Studies at George Washington University", undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Also, Division of Continuing Education and Summer Sessions
  - Plan: Division of Continuing Education and Summer Sessions, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Report on the feasibility of establishing a Policy Center at George Washington University, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Written by Susan J. Tolchin and William Johnson. Existing programs with Policy linkage
  - Report to the Commission on computer literacy, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Section draft on computers, "Replacement of Text-Technology" by W.H. Marlow, Institute for Management Science and Engineering, Status report from the Subcommittee on Computers by John G. Boswell and W. H. Marlow.
  - Series of drafts and revisions submitted by Bob Park and Bill Johnson, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Subcommittee on International Studies on International Studies at George Washington University
  - Reports, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Commission on The Division of Continuing Education and Summer Sessions; Report on research into faculty support and development; articles on the "Role of the Library in Information Management. Confidential draft, communications report, draft report by Edward Caress on programs in the area of communications; Programs listed by School or Division. Report from the Subcommittee on Communications by Ed Caress and Tom Bowles. Revised draft on Programs in Communication by Ed Caress, Thompson Bowles, and Marianne Phelps. "Communications: A New Emphasis, preliminary draft and final draft. Draft, April 30, 1985 by E. Caress, recommending the creation of a Department of Communication with three components: Speech, Radio/TV, and Journalism. Draft recommendation: Institutional Planning.
  - Draft Report, Commission for the Year 2000, 03/21/1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Columbian College, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    William Griffith, Philosophy; Clara M. Lovett, Dean; David McAleavey, English; John Quislund, Chairman, Department of English; Chris Sterling, Communication and Theater; Barry L Berman, Physics; Theodore P. Perros; Phillip Robbins, Journalism and Political Communications; Alan Wade, Communications and Theater; Division of Radio and TV; John Fray, Chairman, Romance Languages Department; Kl aus Thoenelt, Chairman, Languages; Nancy Diers Johnson, Coordinator, Dance Degree Programs; Robert Fortner, Radio/TV; Roy Guenther, Chairman, Department of Music. School of Engineering and Applied Science: Harold Liebowitz, Dean. Appendices: C.M. Gilmore, Chairman, CMEE; R.H. Lang, Chairman, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science; Robert C. Waters
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science enclosure, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    (1): Support for SEAS from the Commission, by Dean Harold Liebowitz. Enclosure (2): Memo to Marianne Phelps from Dean Harold Liebowitz; Charles Gil mpre, Chairman, Civil Mechanical and Enviromental Engineering; R.H. Lang, Chairman, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. Appendix 1: "An Invitation to Join the Industrial Liaison Program", Institute for Information Science and Technology. Appendix 2: Course Load Statistics. "Why should GWU invest in expanding the Engineering Administration Department?", by Robert C. Waters, EAD. Donald Gross, Chairman, Department of Operations Reasearch; SEAS Admissions Office; Continuing Engineering Education Program; Michael P. White Manager, Computing Facility.
  - Reports, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Raymond R. Fox, Professor of Civil Engineering; Harold Liebowitz, Dean, "Support for SEAS from the Commission of the Year 2000". School of Public and International Affairs: Anthony Yezer; Mickey East, Dean, SPIA; Robert Go! dfarb, Chairman, Economics; Hugh Leblanc, Chairman, Political Science. "Keeping the 'P in SPIA"; Howard Gillette, SPIA, School of Government and Business Administration: Norm a Maine Loeser, Dean, SGBA; Philip N. Reeves, DBA, Professor; Gail Owen, Research and Continuing Professional Education; Dennis E. Gale, Associate Professor, Urban and Regional Planning. Graduate School of Arts and Sciences: Henry Solomon Dean,GSAS; E. Caress. School of Education and Human Developmental emmont E. Vontress, Professor of Education; Eugene Kelly, Jr., Dean, SEHD; Jean E. Snodgrass, Chair, Department of Human Kinetics and Leisure Studies. English for International Students: Edgar G. Jones, Acting Dean, DCE & SS; Jon Quitslund. Administrative: William B. Griffith, Chair, Executive Committee of the Faculty Senate; Michael J. Worth, Vice President for Development; John W. Dixon; International Students Programs Paper for the Commission; Mary O. Jones, President, Engineer Alumni Association; Anne C. Webb, Research Associate, Policy Studies; Evert Hollis Bellows.
  - Final Report, Commission for the Year 2000, 05/16/1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Printed Report of the Commission for the Year 2000 (paperback)
- Department planning reports, 1977-1988; RG0037 Series 6; 3 Linear feet
  This series consists of university department planning reports, and range in date from 1977-88. Subjects include continuing education, education and women development, engineering research, planning books for academic affairs, VP & Treasurer.
  - Library manual, 01/1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Columbian College: Continuing Education, 11/1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Arts and Sciences: Education and Women Development, 11/1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Affairs - Engineering and Applied Science, 01/1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Planning Book 1, 11/1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Vice President and Treasurer, Vice President of Development, Vice President of Administration, and Vice President of Research
  - Comptroller, Student Afairs, Provost, 11/1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Planning Book II: Academic Affairs, 11/1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Office files, 1944-1985; RG0037 Series 7; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains correspondence, memorandums, press releases, reports, brochures, flyers, and procedures. They range in date from 1969 to 1985. The materials concern Harold F. Bright; recruiting women and minority faculty; appointments; student grievances; the Division of Extension; faculty identification cards; the Commission for the Year 2000; and peer advising.
  - Commission For The Year 2000, 05/29/1985 --10/29/1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commission For The Year 2000 Publication, 05/16/1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Extension, Division of, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Identification Cards, 04/23/1959-05/20/1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Provost, Office of, 08/27/1969-01/19/1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Provost, Office of Peer Advising, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accession 2014.023, 2010-2011; Series 8
  Arrangement
  Arranged in original order.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by Office of the Provost, 2014 July 10 (2014.023)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains legal documents and documents related to the Welling professorship. The Welling Professorship brings internationally distinguished scholars to GW to deliver lectures and interact with students and faculty in the Business school. The professorship is named after James Clark Welling, who served as the university's president in the late 19th century.
  The material in this series are closed for 75 years from date of record creation. Prior to being open, permission to use this content may be granted by the Office of the Provost.
  - Educational Agreement – Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and CPS, 09/27/2010; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Corporate Agreement #201010 – The Boeing Company and GWU, 12/07/2010; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MOU – GSPM and Estrategia Tecnologias de Informacion Comunicacion Politica (ETICOPOL), 01/20/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - MOU – GSPM and Benemerita Universidad Autonoma de Puebla, 12/10/2010; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MOU – CPS and American Learning Network, LLC, 03/11/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Articulation Agreement – CPS and Northern Virginia Community College (NOVA), 04/01/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - MOU – CPS and Legal and Human Rights Centre, 02/09/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MOU – CPS and Western Studies Institute, 04/13/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MOU – GSPM and Libera Universita' di Lingue e Comunicazione Iulm Milano, 10/01/2010; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agreement – Andean Development Corporation/Corporacion Andina de Fomento, 03/21/2011; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Welling Professorship Background, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Welling Professorship - Becker, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Welling Professorship - Bobo, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Welling Professorship - Brown, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Welling Professorship - Doyle, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Welling Professorship - Eban, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Welling Professorship - Erguder, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Welling Professorship - Freemann, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Welling Professorship - Gaddis, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Welling Professorship - Heymann, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Welling Professorship - Holthausen, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Welling Professorship - Khanna, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Welling Professorship - Kingdon, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Welling Professorship - Klawe, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Welling Professorship - King, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Welling Professorship - Kalb, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Welling Professorship - Lienhard, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Welling Professorship - McDermott, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Welling Professorship - Nader, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Welling Professorship - Poor, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Welling Professorship - Quandt, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Welling Professorship - Reiser, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Welling Professorship - Sandler, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Welling Professorship - Schoenfeld, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Welling Professorship - Schroeder, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Welling Professorship - Sheth, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Welling Professorship - Soloway, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Welling Professorship - Stevens, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Welling Professorship – Von Hippel, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Welling Presidential Fellows (WPF), Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - WPF – Hottelet, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - WPF - Wieseltier, Undated; Series 8 (Box 1, Folder 42)